so one of the roles of the gluteus
maximus is hip external rotation it's a
a huge role for the glute Max the glutax
has the best moment armor the best
leverage out of any other muscle for hip
external rotation and it's also highly
activated during hip external rotation
the problem is when I give people band
or cable exercises like this a lot
you're supposed to use that rear glute
to twist you a lot of people don't know
how to activate that rear glute they
will use all obliques instead um and
different lower body muscles so you got
to learn how to use the glutes and so
here's an exercise that takes the core
out of the equation it just works on the
the lower body muscles and if you can
see down here I have an ankle cuff I am
going to step out a little bit like this
now here's the tricky part I don't want
to set up like this because as I twist
out then this wraps around and there's
no resistance moment arm there's no
leverage I have I'm going to to I'm
going to tweak the mechanical advantage
here so I'm going to line up this way so
this way when I twist I keep constant
tension on this hip okay so I'm going to
put my hands on my hips and I just pivot
on my heel and I twist out I'm using
this glute here for hip external
rotation I only have 10 lb but I do this
for High Reps and you can really start
to feel this glute
burn I'm teaching my hips my glutes my
glute Max how of fire as a hip external
Rotator and then therefore it'll work
better during more complex
movements like swinging throwing
striking and different uh core exercises
where you have transer through the core